Hey, good afternoon.
Welcome.
And, welcome toour session getting bounce right it's my name's albert...
I lead the oversee design team and the honor it's to be part of
this experience that build to share some of our work but,
more importantly it's also for me and the team to learn more about
what you working on so now let's just started and ...of talk more about design so.
And, we from.
Bill and windows ten an obvious...little clip
here we've actually done a lot of design work over the years I think windows again,
I said...an experience that's been evolving for over thirty years...part that journeys
be prior experience it's really exciting but it's also it's for me it's...
and a team there's been a lot of our learning and I want to share some of that today so
rt what's interesting about it it's not just
...a team of designers we have design developers you have design camera
fun encoders
have researchers all and we're all working together to create windows the
product but also we brought in xbox we...services we
...in teams working on these like I'll...and...we had a team that was you know,
the sm buildingaway from...a good work on
...for last couple years and be able...all
...together in an environment about sharing and learning to make windows great
... that's what's so exciting and we...like I said in open environment
were one it's about sharing learning like I said but also I think this is important
...about how we building windows being the openness be able to take
a new ideas I think that's another key part of windows that I've really
enjoy being part of for last year and we work with
teams across microsoft in office in
bing in sky-high outlook one drive one
node all working together debate bring that work into a cohesive and,
I would say hopefully a refreshing and new experience to-you but,
also to allow you to bil on top of that so that's important part.
And, then the other part I want to talk more by I think is really the themes about getting the
bounds fright it's ...in san cisco a beautiful city and,
you saw this morning's talk by such a...
Scott joel alex it's...to me as a designer
...see this theme that's kind of a carrying with all the work redoing in terms of windows
...building bridges how do you connect all these
...that we've been working on the experiences between a pc
...a phones create continuum that spans your experiences
making sure that the things that we create that we design a allows you to be
mobile and not about the device and I think that's what's so exciting the
same time if you about building bridges...hard they take a lot of work and,
to get across the big ocean to get across that turbulent waters someone's
...go forward and go across...and sometimes I feel like that's our team
...designing apps we're trying new things sometimes it gets
across the stream sometimes it doesn't but what make sure is we're constantly trying to build
that bridge to connect at all and that's more important and,
hopefully today I'll share more about some of those things
...create that bridge to the other part of...hash...the golden gate bridge itself
...you familiar of going a bridge...bridge...a bridges
...on tension it's really these cables a hanging out together and there's
this tension in the system and we're going to talk more supports my attention that we
tried create something that spans all these products how do you create
...attention between what's right on a pc what's right on the phone
and bridge that and it's a delicate balance and some things were
so innovating on but I want to rest assured that...do together and we're...take that learning
...also apply to your apps the things that
you're creating so that's really important kind-of theme to take took note of.
And, in terms of their journey that we've been on it is something that I think especially if you're familiar
and this is a design session five years ago when we started the
...we envision what mobile could be were really
inspire by the idea of transportation graphics not just in terms of the visual
...bonus but,
also this clean I would say bowl information design that really helps
you navigate and finer things you want to do and, we were inspired
by great natural systems like london underground the tokyo
...system and of course the work in new york city...
...really took identity and information graphics and...together into
it rich coherent information design... those are things...still true I think
that's still part of...design...it's...still part of our design language and
...make sure that is where we came from and that's who...are still today the other
inspiration in terms are journey was this idea of using graphics system
that really celebrate typography and some people call this the international type of
graphic style or swiss design euler block within the clean.
Use of grid system to allow you create that
...strong hierarchy for information and having
...to stick with it I think that's the part that we really adopted into in terms of
...design system and that's still here today so,
that's the foundation of...five years ago seems like a long-time
and without foundation we worked on we envision phone we took we had back then
which is windows mobile and able to we envision like I said but also I think
bring it forward...in a sense of having...clarity having
...purpose and we did it with some very clear principles which we still
use today this idea that content should be the thing that you care about not
the chrome or not the thing that's helps you just navigate it's really the about the content and
...ensure its clean and open
...the content grieve having space for that and,...then
...typography using typing rich way ...
identified also be navigate and then I think the part that sometimes gets that's well,
it's a good conversation highly things digital that's an especially things like
...a lot of overly use of kind of analogue
icons and things like that what does it mean in a digital world when the icon itself has no
...or needs a new...meaning how do you how to create those
designs so the principles are still with us
...so user todaywith the team but, I would say
we're we've also be evolving and you look at where we came from five years ago to
where we are today hopefully you see that it's a natural evolution and,
it's part of our dna and we're going to keep
within we gotta keep on growing it and evolve it and,
the part I was exciting for myself and a team last year last couple years was we didn't just stop
of the full we had the opportunity to rethink or...vision where the desktop
could go and the work that we did to take the desktop forward I think we
...hot we fundamentally saw that there's an opportunity to bring
the two together and with their work that we shown today with continuum
that's really the vision of how we're going to bring a designs together it's pretty exciting world but,
we didn't stop there this evolution of our design it's really like I said
...journey what we did in threshold was...I would say pretty
auditions and, that's why it's hundley we took our design
system say hey let's stop there how do we continue revolving really think about windows
...the universal platform having a universal design
system that spans across devices like phone and pc but
even more even tv experiences or ten foot experiences or even
...experiences...about that we didn't just say hey
...let's do updated design for the phone we-re?
We fundamentally...think about how do we design whole system for
universal windows ecosystem so that was something that we're working on was still working
on and we have so much share but today I'm just going to give you a glimpse of that and hopefully
what will share more and more on how we approaching the universal windows design and,
they'll be lot more content and tools for you to think about how to create your universal windows platform
app without said the other part was I think this is the...part we
tagged looking at designing a system how do you move forward but
was still be based on a strong foundation and we can use
...analogy...foundation for the city that you do one different neighborhoods
...city be vibrant but it's got all work together those bridges
the to connect those train tracks these to work with each other you want to be able to drive from one
able to another so the foundation for the city needs to be very strong so we did more work on that
and then having comic controls
the just works that makes it easy to develop a thing I think I was a lot of feedback from
folks who were with us for the early phone experiences and windows experiences
how do we create similar apps or similar designs that we were creating and I think
that some of the more things we sharing and then the new thing I think this is the area that we're still
...is cranial adaptive ux that works across
...and it's something that if you're familiar responsive design it's something
that it takes a lot of worked to put theory into practice and
we'll share some of that work in a sessions and the next couple days but this idea of adapting ux and
...reddit...different devices a different context I think that's a
really exciting area for us to grow and then lastly I think this idea of sliding I'm going to share more about
wow how we flighty what are we doing why...and how...how you could be part of that?
So, this universal windows.
A year-ago I think kevin and team
and dave share this idea of universal apps and...easily
evolve into a larger opportunity where it's not just...apps themselves but
the whole ecosystem so that we're going to have one store where all these apps
...to have one sdk having one set of tools having one place where you
can create experiences that works on all these devices that
is an exciting opportunity and for us we really have to be think about how we design we
that we can just design we're just going to make a great phone experience like I said
but really think about how does that experience flex and you hear me he's not
rely words like flex adapt but it is above flexing our systems
that your apps can work that are app can work in all these different devices
so, there's a lot to learn and we're still learning but this is what we the problem
or the opportunity we saw from our design system and,
we definite lots of share and today I think the teams get just announce we'll have a lot of
these learning's on our...center that we just launch so go check that out so how to create
universal windows platform apps go check odessa and there's a lot of get content
their to think about how you could use our system and some are learnings.
And, then the other part.
Especially on insider team sometimes...share a lot and,
maybe that's why so small...these are the concepts that we...a small sample
...hundreds and we design like I say we didn't just look at the phone...look the pc
look ten foot look at even different device form factor that didn't exist and read a lot
of innovations went from mild to while the things
that you would say like wow that's will never work to how do we again...content
be more expressive more personal richer the use of color
strong typography those principles I mention that we've had for last five years how
to apply them even and push...system ...the edge ahead and,
get a sense of how our design can move forward that's the work we did to help kind of build
a platform out and, some of it is making a product some of it will make...the product a
bit later but understand this work constantly pushing the edge of
where I design since we can go and we want you do that
two of us to tell us where we can take the design system.
And, then once we...does the part around common controls having
a consistent set of controls that you can use I think this is an investment that
we fundamental had made in windows ten that we were going to use the
exact same tool we using example for our design uses
exactly tools that you're using to design our applications
design even our system so that's big investment for us and,
you'll see some not work kind of
took place and some of the sample apps that you'll get exposed to but also in terms of how
our first party apps...they'll definitely they'll be part of that same
...control set so...that we learn will put back into the ecosystem
that allows you to grow and make your apps better so that's the part
...make sure it's clear to
...not just creating apps because we could do it ourselves we could do
...way we want to do the one-way and one...together with you so
...an exciting part of...design system.
So, we've
...chose I think the other part that we spend a lot of time on and
carmen jeff we'll talk more about in their session at five o'clock is
wow that's great you're doing all these controls but how do you scale it scaling is
actually hits pretty tough problem and we've done a lot of work in going to
share a lot about how we actually scaling your ux your design so that I can work
on a folder tablet and pc and even other experiences so we thought a lot about how do
we create effective pixels that makes it easier as a designer developer
to design it so that looks right on the different devices and
...something that like if you don't think about and you just kind of change it...different device
or put in different target sometimes just doesn't look right so we spend a lot of time thing about how to create
effective pace pixels and are scaling break point so definitely attend that session later on today
at five to learn more about how we do not but also how you can do that for your apps
so you can effectively make sure you have the best experience
on the devices that you want to target so, that's kind of our scaling effort?
...without said we were also innovating internally how you take these control the scaling this
universal windows platform and apply it to different applications just as
you would and we've been looking at experiences like are media controls
...be...just have one that you could use a few creating a media
rich applications and be able scaled out and use
it apply across all your all these different devices so we actually go to share some of those
you control templates lynette and
...will be sharing thatI think of the session on friday afternoon so that's another tool
...give you...these are the same tools that we're building internally for
...apps...we want to share but also get feedback on what else we need to do
this in the system to make sure that are design works across all these different devices?
And, then the part I talk about flooding I think I'm going to spend probably the necks part of
...high presentation json flighty and why flighty is so critical
and ahs all you a developers and are developing apps
other within your company a or to consumers a customers
flurry is actually let's my philosophy is you have to integrate to make things better there's, there's no
perfect design other back to this tension...this balance there's always a sense of like
well this is the right design or this is the perfect design and otherwise I dispelled
out myth that we designing for billion devices you really trying
to create the appropriate design, design...works for folks that
for different context for different experiences but also allow you to tailor it and I think that's
would be learning and that's why flying so important when we've
...flooding ...the windows insider and, how many of your windows insiders hands up?
That's awesome first I want to thank all you guys because it's been hard I know...kind of rough but,
that's something that we're all used to and,
I want to share with you kind of this next slide in terms of how we doing it so that you could say like
...guys just putting things out there for the second results are no we really
...on it and I think this is a...kind of funny for designer...graphs.
...this one so on the right like I have
suddenly gave wow we do a lot of work reiterating like this is a very different way of
designing windows that we've done before so look at threshold windows ten the
china right kind of gives you a sense of the orange that's how many days or percentage of our cycle
we actually anyway we flooding something and taking...and
...adjusting...design or updating features
like that's proportionally to every other releases it's almost double and
...terms of overall days we're actually much more faster like I said the team was
look at threshold over just over a year-ago to say hey we have this great opportunity great create the
universal windows platform and also move windows ahead and,
we took that spirit and say let's flight let's iterate let's take on this promise
that we want to make a better with our insider and contribute your
ideas figure ideas and contribute to making
our design how we move forward so,
the orange...left really shows while we're doing much more much faster...also
to...same amount time...innovationas windows eight or even windows seven so
I'll hopefully got since we...feedback we are
hearing on it we are learning from it and we are adjusting and,
I think that's the great thing about this new design process we have...can do that?
And, like I said lot of that is sometimes rough edges and if folks...seattle this is
a...what I waterfront looks like right now those can be beautiful someday but.
Like we knew that pay for lot-of folks really
...giving you ...
design that's probably not as complete boa could be that sometimes it's
...still trying out sometimes that hey design hasn't been fully implemented or sometimes we just
trying to learn and, it's going to be...a and for us inside the
...how you see that like, you know, we have...like all...a bug here or the visually
...up the right design and, work...use the conversation and I know for
insiders when you download...up update your machine...phone you said whoa wait a minute
existing the final product what I think that's the part I think we kind
of have the restart level of understanding where hey we want to get those early because
we want your feedback early and...will be rough and even internally we called dog
feuding which...like...sometimes but I somehow I just want to
...we really appreciate your feedback and,
...hopefully understanding that you are hoping to contribute make it better but it will be
rough a and.
Designs I'm going to show you will hopefully show...has really fundamentally help
...evolve...product and make it better even added new things so.
Here's some of the feedback apply into designs and I think I want to focus this
afternoon
...learning especially with our phone flight one hundred fifty one
which kamal pretty recently it was pretty rough
...we knew that but, you also is again one make sure that you-get-a-chance and
...we can...if you and try to understand...design
...needs ago but also hopefully you-get-a-chance you understand
where we're going with it so that when you're creating apps you get to learn from us so,
not senses couple areas...go into an allergist dive
...because everyone always wants to talk about this one it's the hamburger.
And, I can't believe, you know,
the hamburger we're...menu...last time I got so much interest in my hamburger was
...made this rahman burger recipe last year and it feels like wow what like
what what's up with that like what is the hamburger why is that in some ways I totally understand iso
...from I'm hearing things I'm not trying to make light of it and, I want that feedback
to be really clear that we are listening and we are learning and
the hamburger if you step back and just let's just think about it whether they come from what how...
become such a in some ways I would say ubiquitous control for ux
if you go the websites...checking out what's happening withgamma
phones or my facebook page or even
...bankamerica how has it the...
hamburger pattern I would say this control be become so prevalent I think I think I think
...really speaks to the...of or the need for something
...helps you navigate across your app as I think a lot of
...you are design apps...apps it's sometimes hard for someone to find like
...what do I go to find the another section your app another area arts navigate
in a hierarchy we...pretty deep I think the.
The...control allows you to give that opportunity decree that
a global control...kind of like the home to your app.
Hamburger.
And, if you look at the history of...from...interesting back in I
think eighty-one xerox park norm cox had the similar a challenge she was saying hey how do
I create a since a place for my application where I
could quickly navigate across my app and I think that's where it came from an out that was
the problem-solving and I think it still does a good job of solving
...so in some ways it's not the hamburger that's at fault I guess
that's the...look at is how...applied how do you create
an icon a pattern allows you to create that since
...place for your app and navigate across...app and,
I think I think, you know, we've looked at ...designs well maybe it's...strikes
...should be something else but in some ways it becomes such a familiar
icahn I think that's where we landed right now and again,
like I said I'll give feedback...
get feedback from all you that's actually using this control which you could actually use
...sdk and tried out but this is something
out one we're still learning but also hoping the in the...other...
sure if you were evolving how...this control and that evolution has taught us a couple
things...cognitive jeff we'll share some more on that but the hamburger menu
icon others for things that we have to remember we...use it
and we're definitely trying to apply this now there is about navigation that's
...given that sense of place create a clear hierarchy so you can navigate
across your application but also making sure that he only use
the hamburger...appropriate like for a keyboard mouse is actually really great you actually have slide
...shows all the different areas but maybe for
one how to use for on a mobile phone maybe...is not the best in show maybe the app
...or pivots or even tabs can be a better controls and how do you
...tailor your app for those different vices I think that's another thing
we're applying learning then optimizing content layout like I said when you have a phone
call you have a smaller screen and obviously a pc how to take advantage of that and making sure
...content is most important thing as more appropriate to use...what
...do that and then think about again those different input when using keyboard versus
keyboard mouse...touch how do you make sure ...control the hamburger doesn't in the way so
that said that's the hammer...and will be the design a section there's going
to be a lot more conversation and...make sure realistically again feedback and how
in client-but also want to show you in some of the apps how we're doing it and...evolving?
by far the number-one...that we got the most feedback specially in a recent flied is outlook and how
we outlook users here hopefully a lot of great and you guys
gals everyone in this room use outlook because it's a...productive tool
and, email it's very rich very dense line information but,
on the phone it's you have to take advantage of what's on the phone but also the constraints of
the phonetypically on our pc up you're kind of use
...having these three areas having a list of folders
accounts and folders on the left and then the list of messages in the center and then
the message item itself well on a for...ratio one of those and how do you how do you
...again...the attention of hate only show what's appropriate as a
climber experience so I think for us we're still learning how do you take advantage
of controls...you to flex your app for the device and I want to
show that the latest designers design...can be in the current coming...where?
In the earlier flights you saw incomplete development of the command bar
and, I want to...of all give to those to the outlook t because
...been working very hard lobbies controls are actually new and
they're billion from scratch I do like I said we...animal and,
...have these controls that allows us to flex and adapt to
our different devices but now you see that...with those three pains that we had
on outlook we can actually create a simple wait for you to navigate to
less we can use things like in-box your folders but also remain focus on the
list of messages you have...dive in
...message but also the thing this is important part have an app
bar command bar that you could quickly access for most weekly use
actions so it's not a instead of I thing
...like well is a hamburger manures and app...it's actually using conjunction
and, I j flexing are...enough flexibility so that you could adapted
for your application make it more appropriate for the context but also for the tasks you want to help
your customer achieve thing that's really important and showing more the
Other the other feedback we gap a lot on was a
unify in-box the ability to multi select quickly I mean those are things
...team is looking at you start seeing that in our coming builds that we will have app...that's really
quickly accessible and you can take action quickly on that item so,
that's the control that were the team...is building and, getting into bills and,
again, learning house of working...not feedback.
It is not just the email itself...with take advantage of...we're all familiar with how do
...integrate mail with calender ...seems like whoa hey that seems like
...new idea but actually that's how...outlook has always been...was part of the
...was part of mail and...came together I think with the
universal windows platform app of outlook now we billion
...together the other team is making sure that the counters quickly accessible within the
email outlook experience and then if you
want to switch two different views I think that's the other feedback we want to
our mission redress how do we get two million many counter in ones
is all five-one you could actually get to that calendar but you have to actually...tap on...on...a
...date now we can actually make done an action on the command
...and app are and quickly access that so those are the things I want
to make sure that we're addressing that we are trying to make sure it is
appropriate of experiences but also make things easily accessible from one
...use so you see it's all located in the
bottom the screen so it's easy for you to reach of one hand.
And, then the other couple apps I want to talk about in terms of experience revolving I think
that people one it's we've had people unfold four-bit and I think the gallo
feedback on hey where people round or whatever you circles...times
has skip away from like the overall design system but more talk about are kind of
our thinking we reset on windows send one of the key things outwe
really appreciable...phone system was people was a center of your experience and we want
to celebrate that we...make sure that's really important and when you in start or you when you looking
...annapolis how do you make sure people stand out and the thing that we want
...was this idea of using circles reps and people to...you at least have
this visual hierarchy but also celebrate the fact that these
are people the people you care about so that's the one of reasons
...we decide what people in circles and we're going to try to allegheny give us feedback but
I think this helps really in our system the kind of how people stand out from the rest of the design?
And, then we photos again, this idea of adapting and learning I think
that adaptive ux is new so in photos the pc apple washer
of familiar photos collection album where we can make it easy for you to
sword and create collections and albums but also how do you make it
easier navigate and with menu
icon hamburger other keyboard mouse is pretty effective to navigate but for
phone what we shown or tribe is hey, you could actually take advantage of
...where you why you swipe you want use a pivot control...where adapting
...tailoring that have that same app the same photo app to have
...pivot controls so this hopefully shows you that we
are adjusting we are learning but we also appliance idea of adaptive ux into a designs
armoire apps and sharing that with you so, I...shows you the flexibility...system.
The last one I want toggle in this is a work-in-progress and...edge
...new browser it's a contemporary browser it's but it's going to graphics engine that's all
about performance ...of the things we one nature it's consistent across all different screens and we
got really good feedback pay for phone some folks were used...the address
the search box in the bottom how are we just into that what we're still evaluating
we're still learning but something that we're looking at and trying things out so
...sentence more feedback but, also I
think tried out trial new...and unless know-how isn't working so I just
...make sure that we hard listening...important that we have
...system that's consistent but I gain also tailor the different devices so that said I
think the road ahead is continue to evolve...I've only shown couple apps
...lot more we're continue to evolve...like our task
...we're looking...the phone be the same as tablet or pc,
you know, go from left to right to left what's the right way to the set-up we're
trying to feedback on that so since more feedback on...you think about...which
...I think the other areas we continue to evolve and learn is really around this
idea of how do we continue the flight?
But, also continue to evolve are design
...the pc and phone so things like haul
...things like I'll...you-get-a-chance on the our team...think about how do you
may universal windows apps work on all those system so we also
want to feedback on that and,...the if you...get to trial hall and I think
...really speaks you how are design systems evolving even to the future and those are
...that we're considering and thinking about in terms of mccann design
better and more flexible and more taylor and more adaptive and.
I think...we're not just say hey we're going to design windows all of night it's
...evolution and we are continue to push design forward just a little
glimpse like we are continues evolve
the desktop you are thinking about how a gate how do you
flex system how you strong colors typography
design elements...is just a little glimpse that hates not this is not this
...bill...an on where continue to evolve are design system
...it's cohesive it's universal but also making things more personal
and, tailored windows the tensions that we want to work with you to kind of help create that like
balance so have not said there's a lot more to share and I wish I could go on a bit more
and there's sessions the next couple days of is also design area that you get some
...design support...feedback...a tense...those...sessions that we have and,
without also I want to give thanks to everyone who's been
...insiders because as you that helps us make the great products and I
...open invitation to continue given feedback on the flights but also on
the tools that we've been will be handed out odep center ok,
that's the presentation session and we're going to go into a little q in a
...fortunate today to actually have some more folks...teamjeff
fong who leads windows design so he's been a key part of our design team...for jeff.
And, then also...kessler who's our content publishing
team she leads a lot of content...on the dead-center that would be publishing she's
...q and a and also...vehement him and his team hard actually designs
...store the dead-center and even the upgrade experience so cool.
...q and a.
Anyone questions.
I said a quick question I mean everything that goes into the core platform goes
across all devices so like, for example,
would say the outlook was when...programs that goes across the phone windows
...lands and the xbox one which I think
it's just I don't know where is it just...like...
So, it's a universal windowsplatform
...so...on the same frameworks the control set of
...currently is a focus on the phone and pc experience
...pollens you can run universal windows platform maps...that's more of us
...have were can iterate and tried out so...some of xbox it doesn't
...you have to its and...can...and also...question is like,
you know, so,...win-lose...school often.
The universe windows platform like actually go to thesession tomorrow we're
going to talk about some of the media controls so some aspects of the platform
will be more readily for xbox but there's no announcement on is
someone actually announce like...not going to email on tv but, I think is really about the tools
and controls ip create on xbox and on conan pc.
Any other questions.
Where you get...so ...did you collect the data for how people use those
different platforms and that type of things that they do on those?
You know, because obviously you can watch a full-length movie or not obviously...might say you can watch
a full-length will be...your big-screen maybe not going to sit there for our on your tablet or your phone
...collect that data or how did you send out surveys or to handle that?
...user research, yeah, so, there's a combination of what we
...research team that actually goes out and we do usability testing we do.
...and talk to our customers so, that's one part of how we gather data the other part of it
is looking at, you know, you know the...the data
...were getting a through the flights and...a combination of those two things
...at behavior across different devices that inform us on how we
optimize the designs across the different devices and I'll just...this is like a new frontier for us we
spend a lot of time and windows...engineering engagement system and telemetry.
...one of the things that unconscious of looking
at windows ten technical previews is the difference between the
can feel the when thirty-two access that exist and also the new universal...
that now exist I'm just wondering how you see that now...mean...
you got the win thirty-two...a legacy thing that we should really focus on the new-style.
And, leave that the
...old...to the cough themselves as well will be
and design guide...for both within thirty two and for universal
...or how do you how do you see this evolving I mean would
you expect that windows maybe in some future date that when thirty-two type of design
...disappear or do you expect them to be side-by-side for the foreseeable future?
...question and there's different parts of there's one the design and there's the guidelines I could talk a little bit about
...the design things we're doing right nowwith windows
...is a challenge to think about the legacy stuff that we have within all the one-thirty to absent and
...you know,...legacy code...the same time we're looking at maybe some
lightweight things we could do to help kind of bring...to work together looking at some of the
...controls...potentially...those controls that we bring at least a little more harmony across
the new universal space as well as a...to space...looking at some lightweight things we could do to
kind...of those things together as far as guidelines are concerned.
...you'll see that what we did today with you look at the dead-center and
we have design guidance that we've just published today and we're certainly optimizing for what
we're doing right now around the universal windows platform
so taking that and then understanding where we need to tailor our own content
...presentation to all of you to think about where are those places where the line
start to blur and how might you think about what we've had in the past whether it makes sense to bring
a forward and that's and evolution that we need to continue to
do with our design guidance as well so we'll be doing that so I'm glad you asked that question?
Input is really interesting part of that question which iswe've all...windows team since windows
...at least so windows seven in classic desktop is awesome
from mouse and keyboard right it's fantastic and that design works for that and then the pendulum
sort of swung arguably a little too far towards the touch spectrum and
...eight I think we're going back now is like this really nice balance for windows tune is
great for touch and mouse and keyboard so the
design you'll see coming outmicrosoft is this is trying to get the sweet spot.
...previously mentioned about
...pixels...running if the api for effective pixels
available to all types of windows apps or is it just newer...windows...specifically
...js apps and you mention of...going to cover that could your minus with session
...is yet so that's actually...carmen section at five o'clock?
And, in the question is...universal windows platform.
Yes, I believe so yes so we jazz...
Hi, what's been the when you've done your re
years user research would've been the most a effective instruments...found for that?
In terms of the lin in terms of windows ten.
For user I'm sorry for the user feedback in terms of bringing that altogether.
Is it focus groups...a...what's been the best thing you found czar
a that's a very brought we do everything so right...and, I think
...million insiders that's also a very effective set of feedback that we
get okay but I
think more importantly other one of the things that we tried you at least even early on in design
is really understand what is scenario what is howdy actually ...got something ...share more
...design process and saying what was the task you're trying to achieve
but really think of the context...the scenarios we actually do
storyboards we do mock-up and back to this theme of
innovations the quicker you could do a mock-up the quicker you do something code even that's why
...fun and developers the quickie
gets in front of real actual users either in the lab or in the feelin a flight
the better so, one of the things that I think that's so exciting about the way we've been...windows...is
...ability to get out there get our designs out there so my encouragement is like it's not about
research as opposed to getting you design out there and...feedback and,
learning...and up and...supplying
...nature design...your process...a follow-up question real
quick what's the most surprising thing that you found during research and us for...
Surprising one this one.
Well,...there's a back to there's the what is
...prizes...like anything like there's unexpected may
...orders this tension like some of the things we met we
...kinda like hey let's try it out and,
sometimes I came across as being like hey you just doing this and,
I think that's what...a designer I was one of the design team like we try things out it's a
spirit trying to make a product better it's on the sphere of like well
we're just going to do it I think that I think that's a new thing so, any design
you see the intent our intent is always trying to how do we make the experience
...for the customer easier to create a
or just make it more cohesive and I think that's the intense sometimes that gets...
your job communicate intent of the favor things I like to do too is working with
...research user research...if you opportunity to actually go out and visit our customers and
...over time how they use windows in fact threshold, you know, over the last couple of
months so, that's been a great program for us I can partnership with research team is to actually, you know,
go-go visit the people who's been using threshold get can
initial sense of what it was like when they first started using it and over course of
two months ago back and visit them and, there's something just really great about just actually going
...visiting our the our customers are users and,
you know, their homes...workplaces and releasing how they how they use the product?
To me I think maybe this is a sort of collective surprise that we've all experience over the last couple
...is like the surprised at
...in during that desktop design is
...the start menu and the task bar...the jump
...and all that stuff is so solid so powerful and I think
windows...we saw was like a fairly major backlash
about like hey we want that stuff back so it's coming back and windows
ten but it's not just going to be the way it was just going to be coming back and that better that better way that
we're trying to evolve so it's great for mouse and keyboard in touch.
I...of my questions was answered by the technical guidelines
that you have uploaded today but,
I wanted to know how exhaustive that was and if it's
something that is work-in-progress or it's, you know,
...lock-down I want to draw a comparison to
the google material design guidelines and they are very specific and they don't
...not changing right now I'd like to hear a little bit more about...other
...indeo hnds in the same way because we want to have
are designcross platform but also very specific to windows of the same time.
I think we let go of the idea being locked down
on a lot of things these days we certainly motivate...schedule and
are processes tours certain point in time in which...
Stability matters but definitely the content and what we're doing as far as the guidance
...is just starting today with what
we're sharing and we will be evolving that as far as what we see
in material versus what we have out there today think of what we're doing today is sort of
the your further down in the...further down in the details of what you need
to think about as you're trying to design and implement the things that you're seeing a show
you this weekend and we're on that journey towards popping that up
and giving more expression to some of the thinking philosophy around it and some of the things that algorithm
until you today, yeah,
and, actually that's what emphasizes pointers is tension
and it's something that was actually in design...struggle with that you
can be very prescriptive insight like do this and don't do this and,
not be very...just say like well we did this way you guys should try it out and I think
we're trying to find...
were like things like hey the app art it has to be there the
...if you're going to drawn touch device and has to be there I think
we're learning what has to be in the system would must be and,...be more explicit on things like that
allows us allows your app to work across ecosystem more efficiently more cohesive
...but we also trying to...flexibility where you can tailor and just as
...shown in photos and outlook the team is learning
...that balance where should be this is one way that makes it easy for
...to do it to what's appropriate and what's taylor for that device for
...experience so that's the part we're going to be updating adjusting alluring
by all of you helping us contribute to are design guidelines so?
Like I think a great to great next steps for to address that would be like go-go to
...and carmen's session and five because you're going to get into
...much more specifics and go to
...dot windows dot com which just got launched today it's awesome new
...consolidated developer center and you will see design guidelines
there that like these are saying we constantly evolving those but there's a lot there right now.
...unnoticed you've of...feedback about hamburg menus but,
she didn't really necessary address how you in a so fix some of the
concerns think that the biggest concern from people who've use windows phone of the
is perhaps the hamburger menus ...see...top left the...same
...concern with the with the browser and the...was just wondering if
...in a...ios...I can sweat from the edge and axis and bergman you
...to type in the top left...just one if you thinking about that to address the concerns,
yeah, well, yeah, so, we're definitely in the concerns I think, you know,
one thing is too and, you know,...like cake,
you know, the stuff that we have before windows phone the pivots...all those controls they still exist and,
the hamburgers...just another tool and, you know,
that you can use to designer apps and our intent was...we think about it is the
hamburgers a great tool for people to kind of navigate large sections of an application
which is probably...of a seldom perform task than being,
you know, a deep within a section of an application as far as the gesture
...of open the...hamburger we thought about that's not something that's not
consult the...considered right now mainly because a hamburger and
a pivot can exist together so we still want to maintain that flexibility appeal
to just slight left and right really quickly to switch fuse within
...you know, within a part of an application and,
that would conflict with ...as well but and, you...carmen just session
...later today I think that's the guidance we...more specifically like...example I
...of outlook how they're looking to...use actions the
...menu icon with a command bar and app or that's where you most
...use task are so it's I...make sure it's not a it's not hamburger or nothing I think it's
how do you actually create a system that creates up my balance an appropriate and
...for the different devices so definitely that session later today at five
...warm afterwards we're here to talk more and actually learn more what
ideas you have for your app that you want implement...just one quick
...and with the design of ios apps android apps and now windows that's kind of
solve...same suicide...the windows epsy you guys...as the
base appsvery similar to android equivalence I'm just curious where you came from a design
perspective and what you can offer that unique to someone wanted by windows phone
featuring the...on five years ago you design
...feedback them is very clear is very different differentiate against
competition now it seems like it's kind of going the same way there's one what you guys are going to
do free-market design perspective to defray png differentiate the windows phone experience?
...different...something were let's step back and like my type...journey five years ago
I think transportation graphics massimo those the international topographic
stiles timeless...inspiration and in some ways we want to design we timeless
...want to be like hey this year is this style and the next year we're going to put white
...your car
...like we want to create a system that will evolve over time and,
hopefully be...laid-off foundation with
far design our system we can continue evolve and
the evolution of that is really about create experiences that helps you differentiate
thing that's why evolving experiences like core tanner or even spartan
...browsers I think...even holland you can start seeing where designs these bobbing
too and, those are things... we want-to make sure that we have a haveare
designed to capability a system that can actually
adapt in flex you all those different experiences and I think that's why
our designs evolving to allow us to make it more universal?
Yeah, I think it's part of our learning process now too as we kind of think about
what we first approach...this idea of designing universal
...and thinking about how we could create a user experiences across different form
factors we started thinking ik how can we actually...create one system that works across everything and,
over the course of, you know,...the...of the last year we're
fine ik maybe it makes more sense first optimized for certain devices
and experiences so that the expenses really stand out more so as we kind of
start pushing things apart...but I think you'll see a little more expression coming through
of the designs but ultimately,
you know, our primary goal kind of back to you...inspiration
was kinda helping the user the customer really understand what's going on within the system and
really that's what our focuses not so much as, you know, making a statement which is important, you know,
we...ours are design...but also ultimately to make sure that
sar customer trapping they know how to...navigate the system as well.
In the latest versions of the phone version of windows
were saying some changes in how the start screens being rendered in terms of the spacing
between the tiles can you talked a little bit and how that's going to impact the
use of backgrounds on phone because it doesn't look like this very much room in between
the tiles any longer for the background the to show through and also from a consistency sam point
looks to be kind of different from what you're seeing on the start screen in the desktop
...as well as the smaller tablet buildsand, we can talk about,
yeah, so, ...might look a little bit different...should, you know,...spacey between
film between the phone the tablets and desktop the unit
it's working off of the same...grid system is a very
...amazing the...designers work in a start...to think about how this, you know,
this grid system works across all these different devices
...sizes and different pixel densities was actually quite complicated problem but,
we are...a similar layouts across all those things regarding the background
for the phone it is tighter between the two areas but we have is the previous
fun, you know, we have the background kinda show through the tiles will...support that
...as a way for the background to show through and we're also looking attransparency so they
can actually look at the background and...spacing that we're...build is the final spacing on the
...the start for phone I think it's pretty close so yeah, I think that's right...
Two more questions a couple of weeks...
ago you publish first overview of what you're doing with the hamburger
icon and I think that this is very interesting the way you
...I like what you did because as soon as the screen get
bigger the you know, what is a transit transient ux became a
...because it's open automatically from what
understand I would like to know do you plan to do something similar
...that have bar because you...you know, so,...of time you need to purses
...why on phone but as soon as you get on a...huge phone?
It's not...more...tab that you would like its you would like doze
...to expansive that they are always that people don't just cone.
One robot the
...for rover semantically because it's getting bigger uf
plans to help us on that side in the future.
...and it's a huge it's a huge issue right now because...I'm using a tab
...this is a very natural you user control
so is it what is going to be the behavior when I'm getting it on a twenty-seven inches
the screen and if it's a tab that means they'll be probably.
A...this space where there's nothing in it because it's...so you
...so...I may one this year you...if I could by program should say
...just morphine the so that you just give more generally
the user that's a gooddesign challenge like violence and are actually we
...to multiple tabs jan additional content you might have the idea is that I
don't want just...show me three-fourths...different alive right now
and user depending on where the based on the, yeah, that's something I'm not sure
...exploring but that's I think that's a good part of the session we can
follow-up on so there's nothing you're going to discuss...this week about
that what something in the in your right now in on the...
For example, take right now the facebook
app which you stab probably facebook if they have like twenty-seven
shoot inches you would want you to see the for tabs alive right
now not having you to switch because it makes sense so this is the type of issue
that I'm facing right now also in our control support the scaleability but you know, I
...says there's also other things you could do well within the toolkit.
So, that means that will that I will have to decide to decide to
...bar and show something else instead of adding at the boss that more for
...for me so less works to do on...
Great okay thank you are last question heavy-weight...it seems like all
the design issues and...search are driven in large part
...form factors and how you fit things into different form factors?
So, you have small screens and big screens and all that kinda stuff and all of those screens have
frames around them I was watching the whole and stem this morning and
occur to me that.
In that environment you don't really have a display device you don't actually really have a
frame.
So, that in my mind perhaps opens up your design
capabilities a lot into something entirely different, you know,
that's not necessarily just taking an old application with
a rectangular frame and now displaying it on some surface that perhaps
is not rectangular as wondering whether you had any thoughts about how you're going to push
that design envelope in a technology that.
Involves things like...that's...part we're still
...and how...so new for all of us even amongst ourselves that
...closely experimenting and the team is
literally prototyping every day and, hooked like I said definitely go tried
...and right now you can run a universal windows platform app on a
two-d experience but that doesn't like you said that take advantage
...a holographic and how you actually create holographic apps other
...something we're building together...and?
We got a lot to learn and,
how to...design system to support that thank you great hey thank you everyone for a saying
...great session and please give feedback the
...backwards for the session...of blog post today particular can
capture some of this thinking we also have a space down the hall that said, you know, get
...consultation around design so feel free to take advantage and all that
stuff right thank you?